Allen Collegiate Center; Records ua442
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Allen Collegiate Center Records
1968-1978
1972-1976
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
State University of New York at Albany. Allen Collegiate Center
ua442
3.5 cubic ft.
The collection consists chiefly of administrative paper records from the University at Albany's Allen Collegiate Center, operational from 1972-1976. The experimental center combined the senior year of high school with the freshman year of college so that students could earn a bachelor’s degree in three years.
Access
Access to this collection is unrestricted with the exception of a small number of files noted on the inventory.
Appraisal Information
In 2017 student transcripts and education records containing grades were deaccessioned from the collection to increase access. This retroactive appraisal action was executed in complaince with the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA) and in accordance with the approved appraisal and disposition Schedule of the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.
Acquisition Information
All items in this manuscript group were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives by the Allen Center in 1975 and 1978.
Administrative History
The Allen Collegiate Center was established in 1972 by the University at Albany, SUNY’s Board of Trustees upon recommendation of student-faculty governance bodies. The experimental Center combined the senior year of high school with the freshman year of college so that students could earn a bachelor’s degree in three years. The Center was located on the University's downtown campus in Albany, New York.
The Center was an indirect response to criticisms during the late 1960s and early 1970s directed at the higher education system in the United States. Discontents included the system's formality, structure, length, accessibility, and overall practicality after graduation. The Allen Center was directly influenced by experimental colleges New England, especially in Massachusetts, and experimental colleges in Pennsylvania and California. One of the original planners of the Center was its dean, the late Dr. Seth W. Spellman, Jr.
Teaching methodologies included small, seminar-style classes and short-term course modules that emphasized student participation. Allen Center students had full voting privileges and equal representation alongside faculty on the Center’s standing committees, and were encouraged to provide their feedback on the Center’s day-to-day operations and policies. The Center offered a single, interdisciplinary major, "Man and His Institutians" (MAI), which attempted to connect humanity’s social institutions and their influence on contemporary society with classroom learning, extracurricular life, free colloquia, and practical internships. The cohesive implementation of such lofty goals proved challenging for the Center from its planning until its closing. Students who completed the first year of the program had the option to earn their high school diploma from the Milne School, the school connected to the University since 1845 where education students practiced teaching. Allen Center students had several experiential education opportunities and were required to complete an internship within the last two years of study.
The Allen Center closed in 1976 due to the economic austerity measures in the State University system in the 1970s.
Chronology
1967 A select committee chaired by the Vice President of Academic Affairs creates a statement policy “New Patterns in Undergraduate Education” which asks that the University at Albany respond to social change.
1968 The University Senate adopts the policy.
1968 Planning stages begin for an unnamed “experimental college.”
1970 The experimental college is tentatively referred to as "Milne College."
1971 The estate of the late James E. Allen Jr., former New York State Commissioner of Education, grants use of his name for the college.
1971 Seth W. Spellman Jr., professor and past chair of the Department of Africana Studies, is named dean of the college.
1972 After preliminary declinations of large-scale grant requests from several institutions, a substantial development grant is received from the Carnegie Foundation.
1972 The college’s only major program of study, Man and His Institutions (MAI), is finalized.
1972 53 students, referred to as the Pilot Project, are recommended for admission into the center's first class.
1973 158 new students enroll in the accelerated program.
1975 University President Louis T. Benezet makes the decision to close the center, citing budget constraints and university priorities.
1976 The center closes at the end of the academic year.
Scope and Contents
Files consist of records that document the administrative activities of the Allen Collegiate Center. Files contain documentation of planning stages, various committee meeting minutes, conference and professional development activities, correspondence (internal and external), memoranda, course curricula, syllabi, student applications, curricula vitae of faculty, promotional materials, course bulletins, and news clippings. The collection also contains student work, such as the college’s newspaper.
Related collections in the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives include the records of the Department of African American Studies (UA-611), the School of Nursing (UA-629), and the School of Social Welfare (UA-690).
Please note that the folders titled Archival, Rensselaerville 2. Archival 2, and Archival 3 contain materials that were kept by the records creator for posterity and with an enduring legacy in mind.
Arrangement of the Collection
There are no series. Files are arranged alphabetically by folder title.
Education--Experimental methods; College-school cooperation--New York (State); Education, Higher--New York State--Albany; Administrative records; Minutes (administrative records); Annual reports; Bulletins; Clippings; Syllabi; Correspondence; State University of New York at Albany. Allen Collegiate Center; Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching
- 1971 Annual Report, 1972 (Box 1 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 1)
- 1972 Annual Report, 1973 (Box 1 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 2)
- 1972-1976 Man and His Institutions. Syllabi, Undated (Box 1 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 3)
- 1974 Annual Report, 1975 (Box 1 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 4)
- 1975 Annual Report, 1976 (Box 1 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 5)
- 1973 Annual Report, 1974 (Box 1 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 6)
- AC Outlet, 1974 (Box 1 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 7)
- Academic Advisement, 1972; 1974-1975; Undated (Box 1 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 8)
- Academic Probation. Dismissal, 1973-1976; Undated (Box 1 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 9)
- Academic Standing Committee, 1972-1973; Undated (Box 1 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 10)
- Academic Standing Committee [RESTRICTED], 1973-1976 (Box 1 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 11)
- Academic Standing Committee, 1974-1975; Undated (Box 1 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 12)
- Academic Standing Committee Minutes, 1974 (Box 1 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 13)
- Admissions, 1973-1974 (Box 1 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 14)
- Admissions, 1975 (Box 1 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 15)
- Admissions Committee, 1972 (Box 1 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 16)
- Admissions Committee, 1974; Undated (Box 1 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 17)
- Admissions Information, 1972-1975 (Box 1 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 18)
- Admissions Standards [RESTRICTED], 1974-1975 (Box 1 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 19)
- Allen Center, 1972; 1974; Undated (Box 1 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 20)
- Allen Collegiate Center, 1974-1975 (Box 1 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 21)
- An Experimental College, 1968; Undated (Box 1 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 22)
- Application of Matrix Algebra to Social Science, 1975; Undated (Box 1 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 23)
- Archival (1 of 2), 1971-1974; Undated (Box 1 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 24)
- Archival (2 of 2), 1971-1974; Undated (Box 1 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 25)
- Archival 3 (1 of 2), 1972-1974; Undated (Box 1 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 26)
- Archival 3 (2 of 2), 1972-1974; Undated (Box 1 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 27)
- Associate Dean Search Committee, 1972-1973 (Box 1 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 28)
- Atmospheric Science Research Center, 1972; 1974-1975 (Box 1 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 29)
- Budget 2, 1972-1975; Undated (Box 1 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 30)
- By-Laws, 1974; Undated (Box 1 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 31)
- Calculus and Statistics, 1973; Undated (Box 1 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 32)
- Campus Evaluation of Program, 1972-1973 (Box 1 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 33)
- Carnegie Funds. Evans Charles, 1974-1976 (Box 1 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 34)
- Catalog [bulletins], 1972-1975 (Box 1 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 35)
- Catalog Copy, 1972-1975; Undated (Box 1 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 36)
- Charges to the Center. Letter from Mr. Benezet, 1972 (Box 1 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 37)
- China Revolutionary Change, 1973 (Box 1 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 38)
- Closing of Allen Collegiate Center, 1975 (Box 1 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 39)
- College Night, 1972-1974; Undated (Box 1 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 40)
- College of General Studies, 1971-1975 (Box 1 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 41)
- Colloquium Series, 1974-1975; Undated (Box 1 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 42)
- Commencement Reception, 1976 (Box 1 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 43)
- Committee Membership, 1973-1974; Undated (Box 1 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 44)
- Community University Day, 1975; Undated (Box 1 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 45)
- Computer Programming, 1975; Undated (Box 2 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 1)
- Conferring Degrees, 1970 (Box 2 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 2)
- Contracts, 1974; Undated (Box 2 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 3)
- Correspondence. External, 1972-1976; Undated (Box 2 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 4)
- Council on Promotions and Continuing Appointments [RESTRICTED], 1973-1974 (Box 2 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 5)
- Council on Promotions and Continuing Appointments, 1972-1973; 1975 (Box 2 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 6)
- Counseling Service, 1972-1973 (Box 2 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 7)
- Counseling Services. Gabbert and Wallace, Undated (Box 2 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 8)
- Counselor Letter, Undated (Box 2 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 9)
- Course Descriptions, 1973-1975; Undated (Box 2 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 10)
- Course Equivalencies, 1975; Undated (Box 2 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 11)
- Courses Registered with Undergraduate Office, 1972-1975 (Box 2 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 12)
- Curriculum Committee, 1973-1974; Undated (Box 2 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 13)
- Curriculum Committee, 1974-1975; Undated (Box 2 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 14)
- Curriculum Committee Minutes, 1972-1975 (Box 2 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 15)
- Curriculum Proposals, 1972-1975; Undated (Box 2 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 16)
- Dean Search Committee for the Three-Year Bachelorette Program, 1971-1973; Undated (Box 2 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 17)
- Degree Clearance, 1976; Undated (Box 2 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 18)
- Derrick, William [RESTRICTED], 1974-1975; Undated (Box 2 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 19)
- Description of Program for Transfer, Undated (Box 2 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 20)
- Developmental Positions, 1973; Undated (Box 2 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 21)
- Directories of Students, 1972; Undated (Box 2 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 22)
- Discretionary Increases, 1974 (Box 2 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 23)
- Downtown Campus, 1972; 1974 (Box 2 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 24)
- Economy, 1975 (Box 2 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 25)
- Economy Internship, Undated (Box 2 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 26)
- Education, Undated (Box 2 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 27)
- Education Department. New York State Aid Study, 1975; Undated (Box 2 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 28)
- Educational Foundation of America, 1972 (Box 2 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 29)
- Educational Testing Service, 1972-1973; 1975 (Box 2 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 30)
- Empirical Methodology, Undated (Box 2 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 31)
- Enrollment Projections Central Office, 1972-1973 (Box 2 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 32)
- Environmental Studies, 1972 (Box 2 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 33)
- Evaluation Committee Minutes, 1974 (Box 2 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 34)
- Evaluation Forms, 1973; Undated (Box 2 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 35)
- Executive Committee, 1974-1975 (Box 2 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 36)
- Executive Committee Minutes, 1972-1975 (Box 2 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 37)
- Faculty, 1972-1974; Undated (Box 2 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 38)
- Faculty Forums, 1973-1975; Undated (Box 2 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 39)
- Faculty Meetings, 1972 (Box 2 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 40)
- Faculty Meetings, 1973-1975 (Box 2 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 41)
- Faculty Meetings, 1974-1976 (Box 2 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 42)
- Family, 1974; Undated (Box 2 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 43)
- Film Serv 1, 1974-1975 (Box 2 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 44)
- Financial Aid, 1972 (Box 2 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 45)
- First Semester Report to Central Office, 1973 (Box 2 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 46)
- Ford Foundation, 1971; Undated (Box 2 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 47)
- Formal Application, 1972; Undated (Box 2 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 48)
- Fund Raising, 1972 (Box 2 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 49)
- Gift to Center, 1973-1975; Undated (Box 2 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 50)
- Governance Commission, 1971 (Box 2 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 51)
- Governance Structure, 1972 (Box 2 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 52)
- Government Internship, 1975 (Box 2 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 53)
- Grading, 1972-1973; 1975 (Box 2 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 54)
- Graduation Requirements, 1974-1976 (Box 2 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 55)
- Grant Applications, 1974 (Box 2 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 56)
- Grant Proposals, 1975; Undated (Box 3 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 1)
- Grievance Procedure, Undated (Box 3 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 2)
- Guidelines for Early Admission, 1972 (Box 3 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 3)
- High Schools Participating in Program [RESTRICTED], 1973-1974; 1976-1978; Undated (Box 3 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 4)
- Human Development and Communication, 1972-1973; Undated (Box 3 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 5)
- Human Development and Communication, 1973-1976; Undated (Box 3 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 6)
- Humanities, 1972-1976; Undated (Box 3 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 7)
- Humanities Reading List, 1972-1974; Undated (Box 3 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 8)
- Independent Study, Undated (Box 3 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 9)
- Information Request Form Letter, 1972; Undated (Box 3 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 10)
- Institutional Research [RESTRICTED], 1971-1975; Undated (Box 3 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 11)
- Integration, 1973; Undated (Box 3 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 12)
- Internships, 1974-1975; Undated (Box 3 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 13)
- Introduction to the Social and Behavioral, 1974-1976 (Box 3 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 14)
- James E. Allen Center, 1972; 1975; Undated (Box 3 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 15)
- Letters of Support, 1975 (Box 3 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 16)
- Library Committee, 1972; 1975 (Box 3 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 17)
- Library Committee Minutes, 1974 (Box 3 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 18)
- Library Facilities, 1973-1974; Undated (Box 3 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 19)
- Literature and Psychology, 1974; Undated (Box 3 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 20)
- Man and Environment, 1970; 1972; Undated (Box 3 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 21)
- Management and Planning, 1969-1970; Undated (Box 3 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 22)
- Mathematical Modeling, 1975 (Box 3 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 23)
- Mathematics, 1973 (Box 3 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 24)
- Milne College. Three-Year Baccalaureate, 1971; Undated (Box 3 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 25)
- Milne School. High School Diploma, 1974-1975 (Box 3 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 26)
- Naming the New Unit, 1971-1972; 1974 (Box 3 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 27)
- National Endowment for the Humanities, 1971 (Box 3 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 28)
- Newspaper, 1973-1974; Undated (Box 3 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 29)
- Non-Traditional Schools. Dr. Spellman's Letter, 1975; Undated (Box 3 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 30)
- Office of Academic Affairs, 1973-1975; Undated (Box 3 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 31)
- Office of University Affairs, 1974-1975 (Box 3 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 32)
- Personnel Committee [RESTRICTED], 1973-1974; Undated (Box 3 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 33)
- Personnel Committee, 1972-1974; Undated (Box 3 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 34)
- Personnel Committee [RESTRICTED], 1974-1975 (Box 3 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 35)
- Personnel Committee Minutes, 1972-1975 (Box 3 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 36)
- Phi Beta Kappa, 1974-1975 (Box 3 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 37)
- Philosophy of Social Sciences, 1975 (Box 3 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 38)
- Pilot Group and Proposal, 1969-1970 (Box 3 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 39)
- Planning Stages, 1971-1972; Undated (Box 3 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 40)
- Planning Task Force. Collins College, 1971-1972; Undated (Box 3 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 41)
- Planning Task Force. Living Learning Centers, 1971; Undated (Box 3 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 42)
- President's Office, 1974-1975 (Box 3 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 43)
- Profile of Students, 1972 (Box 3 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 44)
- Progress Reports, 1972 (Box 3 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 45)
- Promotions and Continuing Appointments, 1972-1975; 1973; Undated (Box 3 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 46)
- Proposal for a Three Year Baccalaureate and New Undergraduate Students, 1971 (Box 3 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 47)
- Proposal for New Course Form, 1972-1973 (Box 3 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 48)
- Proposals for Development of a Three Year Degree Program, 1971; Undated (Box 3 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 49)
- Publicity, 1974 (Box 3 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 50)
- Readings in Anthropology, 1975 (Box 3 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 51)
- Readings in History, 1974; Undated (Box 3 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 52)
- Readings in Literature, 1973-1974 (Box 3 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 53)
- Readings in Philosophy, 1974 (Box 3 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 54)
- Readings in Political Science, 1974 (Box 3 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 55)
- Readings in Psychology, 1975-1976 (Box 3 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 56)
- Readings in Sociology, 1974-1975 (Box 3 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 57)
- Recruitment Efforts, 1972-1973; 1975; Undated (Box 3 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 58)
- Registration of Program. State Education Department, 1972; Undated (Box 3 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 59)
- Religion and Morality, 1974 (Box 3 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 60)
- Religion and Morality, 1975 (Box 3 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 61)
- Rensselaerville 1, 1971; Undated (Box 3 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 62)
- Rensselaerville 2. Archival 2, 1973; Undated (Box 3 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 63)
- Rensselaerville Three Year Baccalaureate, 1971; Undated (Box 4 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 1)
- Rockefeller Foundation, 1971; Undated (Box 4 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 2)
- Russell, Stanley, 1973; Undated (Box 4 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 3)
- Schedule of Classes, 1973-1976 (Box 4 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 4)
- Scholarship Program, 1971-1972 (Box 4 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 5)
- School of Business, 1970; 1972 (Box 4 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 6)
- School of Education, 1974-1975 (Box 4 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 7)
- Science, 1973; Undated (Box 4 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 8)
- Science and Society, 1974 (Box 4 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 9)
- Science and Society, 1974-1975; Undated (Box 4 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 10)
- Science Technology and Environment, 1975 (Box 4 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 11)
- Second Semester Humanities, 1972; Undated (Box 4 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 12)
- Second Year Curriculum Committee, 1972; Undated (Box 4 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 13)
- Select Committee Response, 1975 (Box 4 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 14)
- Senate Action. Re: Allen Center, 1970-1972 (Box 4 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 15)
- Senior Seminar, 1975; Undated (Box 4 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 16)
- Senior Seminar, Undated (Box 4 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 17)
- Social History, 1974-1975 (Box 4 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 18)
- Social Science Planning Committee, 1972-1974 (Box 4 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 19)
- Space, 1971-1973 (Box 4 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 20)
- Space, 1971-1973 (Flat-file 1, Flatfile 1)
- Statement. Allen Center, Undated (Box 4 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 21)
- Student Evaluation Committee, 1974; Undated (Box 4 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 22)
- Student-Faculty Questionnaire, Undated (Box 4 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 23)
- Student Information, 1973; 1976; Undated (Box 4 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 24)
- Symposium, 1972-1973; Undated (Box 4 (Allen Collegiate Center Records ), Folder 25)